Guide to the Herant A. Katchadourian Papers SC0649
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2002-255
  - Career, general clippings (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Human sexuality class, clippings (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - HK, personal – clippings (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Curriculum Study, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes and outline (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Human life cycle – outlines (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - "Exiting Voices: Evaluating Undergraduate Education through Senior Surveys," 1987 – paper and related correspondence (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Book proposal (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Careerism and Intellectualism – assorted chapters (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Book on adolescence, chapters 5-7 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Book on adolescence, chapters 8-9 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Psychological reactions to puberty – text and sources (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Two chapters on religious life (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Book proposal, Efronia Katchadourian (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - "The Epidemiology of Affective Disorders in Lebanon" – typescript, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Saran, Michael, "The Armenian Question" (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Book proposal, HK and John Boli, "Making the Right Choices" (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Cream of the Crop – thank yous (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - "The 'Premed Syndrome:' Evidence from a Selective Private University," – paper and related correspondence, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Cream of the Crop – Campus Report articles, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaires, versions I and II (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Figures for Cohort study (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of HK's books (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Fundamentals, 4th edition – announcement (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Fundamentals, 5th edition – art work (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Comment on Cream of the Crop, 1993 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Biographical statement by student (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - "Sexual Life of Man" – preface, introduction, corrections (mss) (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – outline and introductory chapter (mss) (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter I Anatomy (mss) (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter II Physiology (mss) (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter IV Behavior (mss) (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter VII Psych Soc Development (mss) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter VIII Auto Eroticism (mss) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Perspectives of Human Sexuality" – chapter IX Coitus (mss) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Hormones (chapter 3, typescript) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Deviations (?) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Psychiatric disorders in Lebanon, Collected Papers by Herant Katchadourian (reprints in spiral binding - copy 1) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Psychiatric disorders in Lebanon, Collected Papers by Herant Katchadourian (reprints in spiral binding - copy 2) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reprints:
    - The Historical Background of Psychiatry in Lebanon, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Psychiatric Aspects of Drug Addiction in Lebanon, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Adolescent Sexuality, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Medical Perspectives on Adulthood, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - The Psychiatrist in the University at Large, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - The Psychiatrist as University Ombudsman, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Analyzing Academic Records for Informed Administration, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Publications:
    - The Nature and Goals of Undergraduates, Faculty Lyceum 1986, CSU Fullerton [HK was one of the speakers] (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - "Cream of the Crop," Stanford, December 1994 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Components in Prevalence of Mental Illness and Social Class in Urban Lebanon, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Social Class and Mental Illness in Urban Lebanon, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Psychiatry in the Arab Middle East, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Sex and the Law, Stanford M.D., Spring 1972 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Research in Brief, Selections, Spring 1987 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Selected Analyses from Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1975-76 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1977-78 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Selected Analyses, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1979-80 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Selected Analyses, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1980-81 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Selected Analyses, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1981-82 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Selected Analyses, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Statistical Study of the Curriculum of 1982-83 A.B./B.S. Recipients, Selected Analyses, Office of the Vice Provost and Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Audiovisual recordings
    - Human sexuality course lectures [audiorecordings]
      General note
      [titles and date taken from label on tape, not case; there is occasionally some difference]
      - Lecture #1, Jan. 6, 1999 - Learning about human sexuality [ZT74 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 2, Jan. 8,1997 - Anatomy of sex organs [ZT75 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 5, Jan. 15, 1997 - Hormones and sexual development [ZT79 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 5, Jan. 15, 1997 - Hormones and sexual behavior [ZT80 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # ?, n.d. - Childbirth [ZT81 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # ?, n.d. - Conception and pregnancy [ZT82 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 10, Jan. 27, 1997 - Sexual dysfunction [ZT106 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 9, Jan. 27, 1997 - Sexually transmitted diseases [ZT107 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 11, Jan. 2, 1997 - Contraception (Dr. Iris Litt) [ZT108 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 13, Feb. 3, 1997 - Evolution of sexual behavior [ZT115 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 14, Feb. 3, 1997 - Development of sexual behavior[ZT116 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 16, Feb. 5, 1997 - Sexual intercourse [ZT118 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 17, Feb. 12, 1997 - Love and affection [ZT132 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 18, Feb. 12, 1997 - Marriage [ZT133 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 23?, n.d. - Sex without love [ZT134 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 18?, n.d. - Homosexuality (panel) [ZT135 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 21, Feb. 24 ? - Sex and gender identity [ZT147 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 22, Feb. 24 ? - Transsexualism (panel) [ZT148 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 25?, n.d. - Paraphilias [ZT158 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 25?, n.d. - Pornography [ZT159 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 25?, Mar. 3, 1997 - Aggression [ZT160 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # ?, Mar. 3, 1997 - Sexual coercion [ZT161 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # ?, n.d. - Cultural perspectives on sex [ZT162 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # ?, n.d. - Cross-cultural perspectives on sex [ZT163 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 11, Jan. 27, 1999 - Contraception (Dr. Kapphahn) [ZT244 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 12, Jan. 27, 1999 - Abortion [ZT245 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 9, Jan. 25, 1999 - Sexual transmitted diseases [ZT246 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 10, Jan. 25, 1999 - Sexual dysfunction [ZT247 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 13, Feb. 3, 1999 - Evolution of sexual behavior [ZT251 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 14, Feb. 3, 1999 - Development of sexual behavior [ZT252 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 21, Feb. 22, 1999 - Gender identity [ZT253 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 22, Feb. 22, 1999 - Transsexualism (panel) [ZT254 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 1, Jan. 6, 1999 - Learning about sexuality [ZT258 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 2, Jan. 6, 1999 - Anatomy of sex organs [ZT259 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 3, Jan. 11, 1999 - Sexual stimulation [ZT260 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 4, Jan. 11, 1999 - Sexual response cycle [ZT261 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 5, Jan. 13, 1999 - Hormones and sexual development [ZT262 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 6, Jan. 13, 1999 - Hormones and sexual behavior [ZT263 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 7, Jan. 20, 1999 - Conception and pregnancy [ZT265 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 8, Jan. 20, 1999 - Childbirth [ZT266 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 15, Feb. 8, 1999 - Autoerotism [ZT267 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 16, Feb. 8, 1999 - Sexual intercourse [ZT268 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 20, Feb. 17, 1999 - Homosexual experience (panel) [ZT275 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 18, Feb. 10, 1999 - Marriage [ZT276 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 17, Feb. 10, 1999 - Affection and love [ZT282 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 19, Feb. 17, 1999 - Casual sex and prostitution [ZT283 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 24, Feb. 24, 1999 - Pornography [ZT284 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 23, Feb. 24, 1999 - Paraphilias [ZT285 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 26, Mar. 1, 1999 - Sexual coercion [ZT287 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 25, Mar. 1, 1999 - Sexual aggression [ZT288 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 27, Mar. 3, 1999 - Cultural perspectives on sex [ZT289 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Lecture # 28, Mar. 3, 1999 - Cross-cultural perspectives on sex [ZT290 c. 1] (Box 27)
      - Hum Bio 3B, Mar. 7, 1994 - Midlife in women (Prof. Carstenson) (Box 27)
      - Introduction; Dev. & Gross (?) Anatomy; Physiol. Of Sex response, 1968; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
      - Functional Soc. Rel.; Eval. Of sex in [illegible], 1968; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
    - Zeitlram (?) Family session [from Lebanon materials], undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
    - Rochester (NY) patient interviews, 1960; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
    - Future Shock, 1971; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27, Folder Future Shock, 1971)
    - Adolescence Seminar, Side I and II, Identity, undated; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
    - Lindemann, Hist. Back. of Soc. Psych, 1968 Jan 25; 1 audiotape reel(s) (Box 27)
    - Unlabeled, May 31, n.y., 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 27)
    - Life cycle seminar #6, n.d. - Biology: nervous system cognition, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 27)
    - Life cycle seminar #5, n.d. - Biology: genetic endowment / [illeg] and embryonal development, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 27)
    - Human Sexuality lectures [videorecordings], Spring 2001 (Box 27)
      - Lecture 1 & 2 - Studying human sexuality; Anatomy of sex organs, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 3 & 4 - Sexual stimulation; sexual response, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 5 & 6 - Hormones and development; Hormones and behavior, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 7 & 8 - Conception; Pregnancy, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 9 & 10 - Contraception; Abortion, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 11 & 12 - STDs; Sexual dysfunction, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 13 & 14 - Evolution of sex; Development of sexual behavior, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 15 & 16 - Sexual orientation; Homosexual experiences, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 17 & 18 - Gender roles; Transexualism, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 19 & 20 - Autoeroticism; Sexual intercourse, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture [??] - Love; Casual sex, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27, Folder Lecture [??])
      - Lecture 23 & 24 - Marriage; Singlehood, divorce, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 25 & 26 - Paraphilias; Pornography, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 27 & 28 - Sexual aggression; Sexual coercion, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
      - Lecture 29 & 30 - Sexuality in western civilization; Cross-cultural, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
    - The Program in Human Biology at Stanford, 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 27)
  - Class materials (slides, handouts, etc) and other work, 17 computer media (Box 28)
  - Hum Bio web pages, 5 computer media (Box 28)
  - Hum Bio web page, 1 optical disc(s) (dvd) (Box 28)
  - Hum Bio slides (text, outlines, graphs, etc.), 4 optical disc(s) (photocd) (Box 28)
  - Charts (genealogy and other) from HK's research in Lebanon (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Charts (genealogy and other) from HK's research in Lebanon (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - RESTRICTED MATERIALS
    Access to Collection
    The materials are restricted for 75 years from date of creation.
    - Recommendations A-G, 1971-1982 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Recommendations H-L, 1971-1982 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Recommendations M-R, 1971-1982 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Recommendations S-Z, 1971-1982 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Dungan, Beth [recommendations, with transcripts] (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Recommendations, 1989-94 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Recommendations (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Report of the Search Committee for the Director of the Stanford Outdoor Primate Facility, June 25, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Estelle Freedman grievance (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Advisees, 1983-84 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Advisees, Hum Bio, 1993-99 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Psychiatry #311/#209 [class list] (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Introductory Seminars, student applications, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Binder: Life Cycle Seminar (Hum Bio 153), – mostly student papers and HK's comments [non-confidential materials removed and put in box 18], Spring 1973 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Adulthood class (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Diana Y. Paul – tenure case?, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Binder: Patients – Rochester (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Envelope, sealed: “personal; destroy in case of death or disability” (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - UNPROCESSED
    - Course evaluations [not yet reboxed] (Box Old 11)
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-063
  - Human Biology 3A/3B Winter 1998 (part 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Human Biology 3A/3B Winter 1998 (part 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Hum Bio: Sex in America (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hum Bio Exam Spring 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hum Bio Syllabus Spring 2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hum Bio Handouts (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hum Bio Lecture Notes, 1983-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hum Sex Enrollment total (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Academic and Career Choice (Hum Bio 32) syllabus notes Spring 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Academic/Career Choice, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cream of the Crop student papers (Hum Bio 32), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cream of the Crop class list, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Adolescent Sexuality syllabus, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Intimacy and Love syllabus, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Gender syllabus, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Career Choice and Development Sources (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Academic and Career Choice Spring 2002 Class Sign-Up sheet (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Psychological Aging notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Midlife Transition Men notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Midlife Transition Women notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Life After Death notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Death and Mourning notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Stress: Coping and Adaptation notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stress: Traumatic notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Stress: Illness notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Stress: Biology notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Adolescence: Identity notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Adolescence notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Adolescence: Erikson – notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Puberty notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Parenthood notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Divorce notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hormones and Sex notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Human Life Cycle notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Marriage notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Career Choice and Development sources, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Career Patterns notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Cohort Study notes, sources, etc. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Studies of Adulthood sources, notes, etc. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Katchadourian press information (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Evaluations, programs, book reviews (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - The Developing Adult: Biological & Psychosocial Perspectives Part I; The SuperStar Teachers Series. 8 lectures on 2 VHS tapes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Developing Adult: Biological & Psychosocial Perspectives Part II; The SuperStar Teachers Series. 8 lectures on 2 VHS tapes (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - MCP 205 Medical School Lectures: Sexual Dysfunction Feb. 14-26, 2003. VHS tape (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - MCP 205 Medical School Lectures: Sexual Dysfunction Feb. 28, March 3-7, 2003. VHS tape (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Program in Human Biology at Stanford; production of Stanford University Media Solutions., 2001; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassettes
    - Group 1
      - Sex and identity, 1974 May 1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Diary of a Dean, circa 1974; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Rat Race II, 1976 Apr 9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Equanimity, Class Day 1976 and Adulthood, S. F. Alumni, 1976 Sep 15; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Non-sexual uses of sex, Napa Alumni, 1976 Oct 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Annual Vol. Fund conference Oct. 15, "Issues in ?? Education" and KZSU interview Nov. 2, 1976; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Human Bio 10, "The genitalia – pride and prejudice", 1977 Jan 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Human Bio 10, "Physiology of orgasm", 1977 Jan 10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Sexual behavior, and Evolution of sexual behavior, Davidson, 1977 Jan 24-25; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Development of sexual behavior, and Gender identity, 1977 Jan 26-27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Sex and interpersonal relationships, and Auto-eroticism, 1977 Jan 31, Feb 1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Human Sex, 1977 Feb 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Freshman Orientation, 1977 Sep 24; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Mid-Life Crisis – Alumni – Stanford, 1977 Nov 18; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The genitalia – pride and prejudice, and Physiology of orgasm, Jan. 13, 1978, 1978 Jan 11, 13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Nature of sexual behavior, and Development of sexual behavior, 1978 Jan 25, 27; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Evolution of sexual behavior, Davidson; and Gender identity, Katchadourian, 1978 Jan 30, Feb 1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Sex and interpersonal relationships, and Auto-eroticism, 1978 Feb 6, 8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Group 2
      - Sexual intercourse, Katchadourian Feb. 10, and Socially problematic sexual behaviors, Katchadourian Feb. 13, 1978 Feb 10, 13; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Class Day Exercises, 1978; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Class Day [speech?], 1981; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Intro to Cross-cult. Chapter - China, Islam, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Intro to Cross-cult. Chapter - China, Islam, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sex in Origin of West. Culture, Sex and Emergence of Modern West, Renaissance and Reformation, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sex in Origin of West. Culture, Sex and Emergence of Modern West, The Middle Ages, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sex in Origin of West. Culture, Sex and Emergence of Modern West, Greece and Rome, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sex in Origin of West. Culture, Sex and Emergence of Modern West, Judaism, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Sex in Origin of West. Culture, Sex and Emergence of Modern West, 19th Century, Spring 1982, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Pacific School of Psych./Commencement Speech, 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Careerism and Intellectualism among Stanford Undergraduates, H. Katchadourian (The Audible Stanford), 1985; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Human Sexuality, 1986 Jan 29; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Transsexualism, Feb. 19, 1986 and Paraphilias, Feb. 21, 986, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Human Sexuality lecture, Gender, 1987 Feb 4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Human Sexuality, Sexual decision making, 1987 Mar 6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Senior Class Lunch, 1989; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Careerism and Intellectualism among Stanford Undergraduates, H. Katchadourian, Jing Lyman Lecture Series, 1991 May 22; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - H. Bio 10, Evolution – Sex. Behavior, Jan. 31 and Feb. 3, ??, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - H. Bio 10, Katchadourian, March 5 and 7, ??, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photographic slides, 1968-2002; Accession ARCH-2014-075
  - Human Sexuality (HB 10) course materials
    Scope and Contents note
    Over the several decades that the human sexuality course was taught, some of the slides used in the class changed over time. Typically, I used 50 slides per lecture (25 slides each in two projectors).
    The slides shown here are usually more than 50 for each lecture. This is because I have included here all of the slides I used over the years including a few that I kept in reserve which I never used. I have done this to provide a broader overview of the material covered in the course during its lifetime. This should also provide potential users of these slides a wider choice to choose from.
    These slides were digitized in two sets and are contained in two Sections: Section #1 has 13 lectures; Section #2 has 12 lectures. Each lecture is in a separate file identified alphabetically. The files in Section #1 go from FILE A (for Anatomy) to FILE L (for Coitus). Only File O, The Study of Sexuality, does not follow the lecture sequence. It should be the first lecture but now appears after File N, Marriage and Parenthood. (The result of confusion between the number zero and the letter O during the digitization process).
    The slides in each Section are numbered sequentially. In Section #1, they go from 1 to 839. In Section #2, from 1 to 1231. (Only the numbering sequence for File O is off for the reason given above). The relevant number is what appears at the beginning after the zeros. (In the original slides, each lecture was numbered separately. Thus File A it went from A1 to A 55. File B went B1 to B 60).
    After this process of ordering the HB 10 lecture slides, I discovered another set of slides which I had used in a course that I taught at Albany Medical School. I have added these slides to the lecture topics they belong to and labeled them as Addendum, rather than Integrating these slides into the HB 10 sequence which would have required renumbering them The slides listed here are only those that required comments or explanations. Hence, there may be gaps in their sequence. For instance, in FILE A, slides 1-2 are followed by slide 7. These are mostly for identification rather than instructional purposes.